Craig Parks

408-463-6415 • craig@craigrparks.com

Customer Success Leader

Proven leader with extensive experience in the building of service, support and sales organizations to take companies from the pre-revenue stage up to hundreds of millions of dollars in revenue. Exceeded all performance goals in roles directing customer success; pre-sales; professional services; education and support at both mature companies and startups, including Bromium, BMC Software, InterVision, XenSource, Marimba and Tivoli.

A creative and hands-on leader with the experience and skills to grow revenue, increase profitability, acquire customers and provide world-class customer service.

Professional Experience

VP, Customer Success, PowWow Mobile, San Francisco CA

2016-Present

Created a customer success organization that delivered a 94% customer retention rate. Produced service offerings, customer success practices, support processes, and training offerings that provided customers with rapid time to value, world-class support and provided PowWow with excellent references and increased revenue.

- 140+% YOY Revenue growth.
- Achieved a 94% Renewal Rate.
- Grew customer base by 4x. Customers included: Delta, BP, JPMC, Wells Fargo and Fannie Mae.
- Created an App Factory that provide increased services elasticity at a 40% margin.

VP, Customer Success, Bromium, Cupertino CA

2015-2016

Created a customer success program to drive product adoption and increase revenue. Built standardized offerings, methodologies and reporting that drove customer deployments and created reference accounts.

- Increased the number of closed up-sell opportunities by 3X.
- Expanded product footprint by 150%.
- Grew the number of services customers by 4X.
- Improved customer satisfaction through standardized delivery processes.
- Improved the time to value for our customers by 50%.

Sr. Director, Global Services Center of Excellence, BMC Software, Santa Clara CA 2011-2014

Created go-to-market strategy, standardized offerings and best practices for the Global Services team for Remedy, Remedy OnDemand, MyIT, Smart IT and ADDM.

- Increased MyIT services and product revenue by 3X.
- Improved the average deal size 15% by creating standardized offerings.
- Achieved double-digit increase in the percentage of revenue driven by standardized service offerings.

Craig Parks

VP, Customer Services and Operations, InterVision, Santa Clara CA

2007-2011

Directed business strategy, vendor relations, business development, customer services and IT.

- Increased revenues from \$63 Million to \$110 Million within four years.
- Grew sales 175% by improving account coverage and cross selling of InterVision's product line.
- Developed standards for the negotiation and execution of customer and vendor contracts.
- Improved customer satisfaction by enhancing the deal review process and services enablement.

VP, Customer Services and Operations, XenSource, Palo Alto, CA

2005-2006

Responsible for driving revenue by creating and delivering service and support offerings.

- Achieved customer satisfaction ratings of 90+%.
- Established a global customer success group to provide 24x7 support for XenSource customers.
- Instrumental in the creation of the product packaging, pricing and services for XenSource's products.
- Created and maintained IT infrastructure, facilities and corporate services.

VP, Customer Services, Marimba, Mountain View, CA

1997-2004

Responsible for the worldwide customer services teams, which included: customer support, pre-sales engineering, professional services, enterprise account management and education services.

- Instrumental in the growth of annual sales to over \$50 Million in revenue.
- Responsible for \$16+ Million in services and support revenue.
- Developed a successful proof of concept methodology with a 95% close rate.
- Established and grew the professional services group to a seven figure quarterly run rate.
- Implemented global 24x7 support infrastructure, process and procedures to provide technical support and escalation process.
- Obtained a renewal rate of 90+% over 3 years.
- Reduced engineering escalations from 20+% to less than 1%.

Previously held positions

- Director, Systems Engineering, Tivoli Systems, Campbell, CA
- Engineering Services Manager, InterCad, San Jose, CA
- Computer Aided Engineering Specialist, FMC, San Jose, CA
- Gas Systems Analysis Engineer, PG&E, San Francisco, CA

Education

Bachelor of Science, Mechanical Engineering

California Polytechnic University, San Luis Obispo, CA